I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
I'll come and get you; I'm armed, always ready to fight
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
So don't take all of the blame
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
We're wrong as well
Oh, wait, don't take all of the weight
You always do
No signs, no lights
There will always be something you cannot control
Such a mess all over
We will overcome
Don't kill your hopes
Your salvation has begun
You make me realize who I need
No sounds, no light
Such a mess all over
I'll be there, hold on
Don't kill your hopes
They'll change you somehow
You make me realize who I need
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
I'll be there, hold on
The shadows appear
Illusions are born
They'll change us somehow
So where are you now?
The fallen angels you run with don't know
I'll reach you by dawn
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
The shadows appear
Illusions so bright
Torn old sepia photographs show
To fall and then just to run
Our fragile preious world
Let them know it is the pain that makes us so human after all
Must discard it, respond to the call
Don't want to deceive me, you follow the truth
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&冰蝶   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
You found your precious world, but discard it, respond to the call
A New
Family
ベッドの下から絶対に出て来ちゃダメよ
Whatever you do,
do not come out from under the bed!
But...
お姉ちゃん
Sis!
Hey, Lacus.
おい　ラクス
HQ's calling.
本部からの呼び出しだ
Hm?
Oh, got it.
分かった
You've eaten already, René?
レイでは済ませたのかい
Sis...
お姉ちゃん…
で　早乙女与一
Saotome Yoichi.
今はお前のもっとも深い部分の記憶を再生しているわけだが…
Right now, we're reliving your innermost memory.
Sis, you're alive?
お姉ちゃん　生きて…
もちろん　死んだよ
Well, she's not, of course.
Big bro...
お兄ちゃん
Did I wake you up?
起こしちゃったか　ごめんな　未来
My bad, Mirai.
No...
How are you feeling?
具合は
I'm doing okay. I feel better today.
大丈夫　今日は調子がいいんだ
そうか
That's good.
Are you hungry?
腹は減ったろ
I'll get you something to eat.
何か食いもん取ってくるよ
Bro...
お兄ちゃん
you know, if I'm just weighing
you down, then you can—
あのさ　もし邪魔だったら　私のこと…
Don't even start.
黙れ　バカ　邪魔なはずないだろ
You're not a bother in any way.
でも　このままじゃお兄ちゃんも…
But if this keeps up, you'll also...
でもじゃない
No buts!
If we die, we die together!
死ぬ時は一緒だ
No, don't say that...
ダメだよ　そんなの
だってお兄ちゃん　毎晩泣いてるじゃん　辛いって
I see you cry every night about how hard it is,
about how you want to leave me.
私を捨てたいって
Why would you say such...
なんで…そんなこと…
Because you're a greedy human being who only thinks for his own benefit,
それはお前が自分のことしか考えてない身勝手な人間だからだよ
君月士方君
Kimizuki Shihou.
お前が　鬼
You're the demon.
Indeed I am, but this is no mere hallucination.
そうだが　これは幻覚じゃないぞ
ワシはお前の記憶を利用しているだけだ
These are your memories—
これはお前の中にある真実
the truth within you.
Don't give me that bullshit!
ふざけるな
Hm?
こいつはまっ　なんとかなりそうだな
Looks like he'll make it through, at least.
やあ　優ちゃん
Hey, Yuu.
Yuu, who ran away and
abandoned his precious family.
僕らを見捨てて逃げ出した優ちゃん
I don't have time for your game of charade.
俺の大切な家族を真似るのはやめろ
Oh? I thought I was poking at your softest spot,
あれ
君の一番弱い場所に触れているつもりなんだけど
まるで動揺してないねぇ
but it's almost as if you couldn't care less.
不思議だ　なぜかな
How strange. I wonder why?
I know of these mind games
you demons like so much.
てめぇら鬼のやり口はもう分かってんだ
いいから諦めて俺に力を寄越せ
Just give up, and surrender your power to me.
ミカ
Mika!
Oh, that explains it.
なるほど　君は一度鬼に触れているのか
It seems you're not a stranger to my kind.
You have hopes of defeating me just because
you've dealt with that Myou-Ou trash?
でも下位の明王に触れたくらいで　僕に勝つつもり
I can toy with your flimsy
little heart however I please.
君程度の心など　どうとでもいじれるのに
Shut up.
黙れよ　いいから俺に力を寄越せっつってんだ
I'll say it again: give me your power!
It belongs to me now!
てめぇの力は俺のもんだ
でも　なぜそんなに力を求める
Why do you wish for power so desperately?
Is it for revenge?
復讐のためかい
Of course!
そうだ
Because you lost those precious to you?
大切なものを失ったから
That's right.
そうだ
初めてできた家族を失った
I lost the family that I never thought I'd have.
That must have been tough.
それは辛かったねぇ
Very well.
いいよ　復讐のための力が欲しいなら
If you desire power for revenge,
then I can give it to you without restraint.
僕は無限に力をやれる
So...
じゃあ…
でも　まだ足りないよ　優ちゃん
But it's still not enough, Yuu.
I can't help you unless you unconditionally devote yourself to revenge.
もっともっと
復讐のためだけに生きてくれないと
力はあげられない
The little girl speaks the truth.
そうだね　その子の言う通りだ
君には力はあげられない
So I can't give you my power after all.
Hold on!
待てよ
優ちゃん
Yuu.
また僕らを置いてく気なの
Are you going to leave us again?
また一人でどこかに行っちゃうの
Are you going to run away on your own again?
Yuu wouldn't do something like that, right?
優兄ィはそんなことしないよね
また　私たちと一緒に暮らすんだよね
You'll come live with us again, won't you?
Isn't that right, Yuu?
そうだよね　優兄ィ
愛を捨ててよ　優ちゃん
Relinquish your love, Yuu.
僕らはそれが一番苦手なんだ
It's the one thing we hate the most.
欲望は好き　でも愛は嫌い
We love lust,
and loathe love.
与一　君月　シノア　仲間　何それ
Yoichi,
Kimizuki,
Shinoa...
Friends?
You can't be serious.
Are you going to forsake us
and be the only one living happily ever after?
優ちゃんだけ友達作って　幸せになるつもりなの
そ　それは…
Th-That's...
優ちゃんだけ生き残って　そんなのずるいよ
As the only one who survived,
don't you think you're being unfair?
私たちを置いて一人で逃げて
How could you abandon us, run away,
学校通って友達作って
replace us with new friends,
and completely forget about us?
私たちのことなんかさっぱり忘れて…
You're wrong! I haven't forgotten about—
違う　忘れてなんか…
じゃあ　友達なんか捨ててよ
Then cast your friends aside.
優ちゃんの家族は僕たちだけでしょ
We're the only family you need, Yuu.
Stop.
やめろ
私たちの敵を討ってくれるんでしょ
You're going to repay them
for what you've lost, right?
Stop it.
やめろ
You're going to lead a life of vengeance, right?
復習のために生きてくれるんでしょ
Stop it!
やめろー　てめぇらガタガタうるせぇ
All of you, shut the fuck up!
いいから　俺に力を寄越せ
Cut this shit out, and give me your power!
I...
俺は…俺には…
I need the power to protect those precious to me!
全部を守るだけの力がいるんだよ
Oh, my.
What an incredible contradiction of love and lust entwined.
愛と欲望が絡み合った　すごい矛盾
これだから人間は世界を壊す
This is why humans bring ruin upon themselves.
いいだろう　気に入った
Fine. I like you.
But my loyalty will only be
as strong as your conviction.
君の心が強い限り　従ってやる
だが一瞬でも心が弱いと思ったら　君の体をもらうよ
If your heart wavers, even for the slightest moment,
your body will be mine.
Sure, that's fine by me!
問題ない
My name is Asuramaru.
僕の名は阿朱羅丸
力が欲しい時は名前を呼んでくれ
Call upon me when you need my power.
Asuramaru...
阿朱羅丸
Oh, and one more thing.
あともう一つ
主となった君に情報をあげようかな
I'd like to make my new master aware of some information.
Information?
情報
You're something like a mix of odd parts.
君ね　少し妙なものが混じってるよ
As it stands, there's already
ten percent of you that isn't human.
すでに一割くらい人間じゃない
もしかして人間どもに何か良からぬ改造されてるんじゃないかな
Could the humans be experimenting on you?
What? What does that—
そりゃ一体…
Never trust a human, Yuu.
人間を信じるなよ　優
人間は吸血鬼よりも　鬼よりも怖いよ
They're far more terrifying than any vampire or demon.
Ha. Saying that to a human feels a little weird.
って　人間の君に言うのは妙な気分だけど
What? Seriously, what are you going on about?
ちょっ　だからお前　何の話を…
じゃあこれで　契約は完了した
With this, the contract has been completed.
僕は君の力となろう　刀となろう
I'll lend you my power.
Open your eyes,
strengthen the fierce desire within you,
目を開け　君の強い欲望を膨張させて
and pave a new path unto the world...
世界を切り開いてみせろ
百夜優一郎
Hyakuya Yuuichirou!
Oh, did it go well, Yuu?
うまくいったか　優
Guren...
グレン
当たり前だろ
Of course it did.
余裕こいてんじゃねぇよ
Don't get too cocky.
It took you long enough.
調伏にどんだけ時間かけてんだよ
お前も成功したのか
Did you make it too?
当然だ
Naturally.
与一は
How about Yoichi?
Who are you?
君は　一体…
お前が呼び出したんだろう
You summoned me, didn't you?
鬼呪装備を手に入れて　姉の敵を討ちたいと言って
You wished for an Infernal Arm that could avenge your sister.
Oh, that's right...
そうか…
僕　鬼との契約中だった…
I was in the middle of contracting with a demon.
じゃあ　君が鬼なんだ
So you're the demon?
Sure am.
そうだ
意地悪な姿してるなぁ
That's a cruel form to take.
お前は間抜けな顔をしている
And all you can do is grin like an idiot.
よく言われるんだけど
I get that a lot.
で　お前は力が欲しいのか
So, you want power?
What?
お前の心に触れたが
I tampered around with your heart, but there wasn't a single shred of vengeance to be found.
いまいち強い復讐心を見つけられなかった
あるのは安定　優しさ　他者への愛情…
Only stability, compassion, and love for others.
どれも俺は嫌いだ
All the things I hate.
Th-That's not true.
そ…そんなことないよ
I want to avenge my sister's...
僕はお姉ちゃんの敵を…
That's a lie.
嘘だな
You're glad that it was her instead of you.
お前は自分だけ助かったことを喜んでいる
N-No, that's not...
そ…そんなこと
You hate conflict.
それに争いを嫌っている
仲間が死ぬことを　家族が死ぬことを
You don't want your friends,
nor your family to die.
No, you have no desire for any bloodshed.
いや　自分が誰かを殺すことを
殺せない復讐心？　なんだそれは
Vengeance that can't kill?
Give me a break.
あまりに欲望が足りない
You lack lust.
そしてそういうやつは　嫌いだ
I despise people like you.
That's why I'll avenge her in your stead.
だから俺が　お前の代わりに敵を討ってやろう
体を寄越せ　人間
Succumb to me...
pathetic human!
You don't even have enough desire to fight back.
抵抗するための欲望も足りない
やはりお前はだめだな
You really are useless after all.
俺の主には相応しくない
The likes of you aren't suited to be my master.
Oh, man. Bad news.
まじいな
与一はやっぱちょい力が足りなかったか
Yoichi just didn't have what it took, I guess.
でもまぁ　「黒鬼」に挑戦して三分の二が成功は上乗だろう
But I suppose two passing candidates out of three isn't too bad.
What?
What's going on?
一体どういうことだよ
人間が一二三四
I spy with my little eye... one, two, three, four humans.
おまけに全員鬼呪装備持ちか
All with Infernal Arms, too.
Humans really are troublesome.
これだから人間は厄介だ
弓よ
Come, my bow.
All right.
よし　鬼呪装備も手に入ったことだし
Now that you guys have your Infernal Arms,
吸血鬼殲滅部隊　月鬼ノ組での初任務をお前らにやろう
here's your first job as the vampire extermination unit
known as the Moon Demon Company.
Yuu. Kimizuki.
優　君月
人喰いの鬼が出た
There's your murderous demon.
Deal with it.
お前ら二人で始末しろ
危険な人間は　皆殺しにしよう
Oh no, whatever shall I do?
Let's slaughter them all.
Yoichi?!
与一
Whew.
やっぱ鬼の力がそのまま出てくると
I guess the raw strength
of a demon alone is pretty powerful,
even if it hasn't fed on the lust of its victim.
欲望を食ってなくてもそこそこつええなあ
Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
グレン中佐
May I share my opinion?
少しご意見しても
Hell no.
だめだ　黙ってろ
Pipe down.
But this situation is...
しかし　この状況は
Hey, Guren!
おい　グレン
What the hell do you mean, deal with it?!
始末ってどういうことだ
Yoichi is our comrade!
与一は仲間だぞ
What?
That thing's a demon no matter how you look at it!
ありゃどう見ても鬼だろうが
Kill it now, and put him out of his misery!
早く殺して楽にしてやれ
ざっけんな
What the hell?!
仲間殺せるわきゃねえだろうが
There's no way I can kill a comrade!
Don't get smart with me!
生言ってんじゃねえ
This is the Moon Demon Company!
ここは月鬼ノ組だぞ
あるのは修羅の道だけだ
We march on the path to Hell!
Or did you only come here
to play meaningless games of revenge?
それともてめぇらは復讐ごっこでもしに来たのか
If you feel like getting yourselves killed, great.
殺されたきゃ好きにしろ
だが与一はもう戻らない
But Yoichi won't ever come back!
Shit...
くそ
てめぇらが軍人だって胸張ってんなら　やるべき事をさっさとやれ
If you take any pride in being a soldier,
steel yourselves and get the damn job done!
く…くそ　くそ　くそがあ
F-For fuck's sake...
Damn it!
What was...
なんだこれ
Yuu!
優
Give Yoichi back,
与一を解放しろ　化け物があ
you fucking monster!
よし
Got him!
You idiot!
馬鹿が　気を抜くな
Don't let your guard down!
The demon is inside Yoichi, not the weapon!
鬼は武器じゃなく与一の中にいるんだぞ
やめろ　与一を殺す気か
Cut it out!
Are you trying to kill Yoichi?!
What's this?
なんだそれ　お前ら俺を殺せないのか
You guys can't even bear to kill him.
Yoichi, snap out of it!
与一　正気になれ　鬼になんか負けてんじゃねぇよ
Don't let a shitty demon get the better of you!
俺と一緒に吸血鬼倒しに行くんじゃなかったのか
Weren't you going to kill the vampires with me?!
グレン中佐　これは少しやりすぎじゃないですか
Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
I believe this has gone a little too far!
They're not ready yet.
まだ無理です　彼らに与一さんを殺させるのはやめてください
Please don't make them kill him!
Oh?
いっつもクールなわりにあいつらには優しいんだな　シノア
You're usually so distant and cool,
but you actually like these kids, don't you?
Have they grown on you?
情でも湧いたか
Lieutenant Colonel!
中佐
じゃあ　お前がやれよ
Then you do it.
Bear the cross for them.
あいつらを罪悪感から救ってやれ
What?
なんだよ　お前も手を汚すのは嫌なのか
You'd rather keep your hands clean, huh?
That's the first time I've seen your cute side.
初めて可愛いところ見せたじゃねぇか
与一　正気に戻れ
Yoichi, get a grip!
Don't you dare lose to a demon!
鬼になんか負けるんじゃねえ
Hush, child.
うるさい
死ね
It's time to die.
Do it.
やれよ　俺は仲間を殺せない
I won't kill a friend.
I promised that I wouldn't abandon them.
見捨てないって決めたんだ
And, Yoichi...
そして与一　お前も俺を殺せない
you can't kill me either.
If you're the same as me...
お前が俺と一緒なら
If your family died right before your eyes,
目の前で家族を失ったんなら
仲間を殺せるわけがないんだ
then there's no way you can kill a friend!
Are you out of your mind?!
んなっ　馬鹿か
So wake the hell up already!
だから早く目を覚ませよ　馬鹿与一
You freaking moron!
Here we go...
じゃ
Die.
死ね
与一
Yoichi!
Are you going to hide under the bed and watch your family die again?!
てめぇはまたベッドの下で　家族が死ぬのを見てるつもりか
Get your damn ass out of there already
and protect your friends!
いいから　さっさと出てきて仲間を守れ
Yoichi!
与一
Whatever you do,
do not come out from under the bed!
ベッドの下から絶対に出てきちゃダメよ
ぼ…僕は　僕は
I...
I don't...
I don't want to run away anymore!
本当はもう逃げたくないんだ
だから　だから僕に大切な人を守れるだけの力を
That's why...
That's why I need the power
...to protect those dear to me...
The power to annihilate all my enemies...
敵を全て壊せるだけの力を　寄越せよ　鬼
Give it to me,
demon!
Whoa, there.
優
嘘
No way...
I-Is he back?
も　戻ったのか
There, there.
よっし　よく戻った
Welcome back.
Yuu...
優くん
You sure took your damn sweet time!
戻んのがおせえ
Wh-Why kick me, asshole?
な…なんで俺なんだよ
ゆ　優くん
Y-Yuu!
まさか　中佐はこうなると
Is this what you anticipated, Lieutenant Colonel?
I thought I told you to pipe down.
うるさい　黙れ
俺は別にガキが死のうがどうでもいい派だ
I couldn't care less if some kid died.
Or so you say, but your expression near the end suggested otherwise.
その割には最後ちょっと焦ってたように見えましたけど
Ow!
痛っ痛っ
You have a gift.
お前には才能がある
なのに姉貴を助けられなかったことに負い目を感じて
You felt guilty for leaving your sister helpless,
生きる欲望が足りてない
and lost your desire to live.
But you found it today, didn't you?
だが今日　それを見つけられたろ
お前が生きる理由は　今日お前を助けてくれた仲間を守ることだ
Protecting the friends that saved you
is enough reason to live.
Revenge?
復讐？　んな小さいものに囚われんな
Don't get hung up on something so trivial.
てめぇも同じだ　馬鹿
Same goes for you, idiot.
Ow.
いて
Forget about your previous family.
昔の家族はもう忘れろ
What?
Don't be ridi—
ふざけ…
This is your new family.
ここにいるのが新しい家族だ
Put your life on the line for them, dumbass.
お前は今いる家族に命を懸けろ　馬鹿が
There's nothing to be found in the past.
過去には何もねぇぞ
It's the future that has things to offer.
あるのは未来だけだ
うるせぇよ
Whatever.
Anyway, since you've all got your Infernal Arms,
さって　鬼呪装備も手に入れて
ちょ～とチームワークっぽいことが出来てきたから
and you kinda worked as a team,
そろそろ一回前線出てみっか
I suppose we can head out to the front lines.
The front lines?!
前線
Yeah.
ああ　関西方面の吸血鬼どもが新宿奪還を計画していることがわかった
We found out that the vampires from the Kansai region
are planning on reclaiming Shinjuku.
その辺の調査に行くぞ
We're going to investigate that area.
So, we can hunt vampires?!
じゃあ　吸血鬼狩れんのかよ
W-We're going out into the field already?
い…いきなり実戦なの
Don't we get a break or something?
ちょっと休みとかないのかよ
Sheesh.
ガキ育てんのも疲れんなあ
Raising kids sure is a pain in the ass.
もうすぐ東京に到着します
We will soon be arriving at Tokyo.
Attacks from the Japanese Imperial Demon Army
池袋　新宿　渋谷近辺では日本帝鬼軍からの攻撃が予想されます
are expected around Ikebukuro, Shinjuku, and Shibuya.
Please be careful.
気をつけてください
だってさ　ミカ
Did you hear that,
Mika?
まずは新宿か
So Shinjuku is first.
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shi ni torikago sumi
Caged in the city I call home
kogoeta tsubomi no okizarigoe
A frozen bud cries silently
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
kurameta kioku no kage
Turning the shadows of my memories ever darker
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you need love tonight
Just as you need love tonight
足掻く　Red Light
akaku red line
We're walking a red tightrope
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kakiwaketa neon to
As the neon lights we leave in our wake
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
And the reasons we carved out for ourselves
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
Run parallel
Come on break it down for me!
Come and break it down for me
come and break it down for me
A river will flow
i'll lead the way home
And I'll lead the way home
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
i'll lead the way home
Though the shooting stars pay no heed to us
kiganai hoshi demo
negai nasazu
Leaving our wishes unfulfilled
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
negai nasazu
zange sae kawaita yogoshi ga
In a depraved world devoid of guilt
kanadetai tone nara
The tone you evoke
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadetai tone nara
Turns dusk a madder red
komorebi no aka ga sawagu
Next time, on Seraph of the End:
次回　終わりのセラフ
Mitsuba's
Squad
"Mitsuba's Squad."